Herman A. Gray Papers 5224
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Herman A. Gray Papers
1937-1951
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Gray, Herman A.
5224
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
The collection is composed of the minutes of the meetings of the Council and related materials for the years 1942, 1947, 1948, 1949, and 1950, but it is not complete. It contains reports of the New York State Department of Labor on employment agencies and unemployment, and a number of pamphlets on the various aspects of unemployment insurance.
3834363
Biographical / Historical
The Council was first appointed by Governor Lehman in 1935. There were 9 members, three representing the public, three for the employers and three for labor. Dr. Gray, a professor in the Law School of New York University, was elected chairman. Its original function was to advise on an unemployment insurance law for N.Y. State. In 1949 it was assigned the task of the operation of the Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance.
Scope and Contents
The collection is composed of the minutes of the meetings of the Council and related materials for the years 1942, 1947, 1948, 1949, and 1950, but it is not complete. It contains reports of the New York State Department of Labor on employment agencies and unemployment, and a number of pamphlets on the various aspects of unemployment insurance.
Major correspondents in the collection are Herman A. Gray (chairman, New York State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance), Edward Corsi (industrial commissioner, New York State Department of Labor), Milton O. Loysen (executive director, Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance), Frieda S. Miller (industrial commissioner, New York State Department of Labor), Meredith B. Gwinn (director, Bureau of Research and Statistics), Lillian Chutroo, Nathan Morrison (acting executive secretary, State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance), Robert C. Goodwin (director, Federal Security Agency, Social Security Administration), and M. Joseph Tierney (director, New York State Employment Service). The collection includes compiled volumes of information (1949) on organization and operation of New York City offices of the New York State Employment Service (industrial, needle trades, shipbuilding, commercial, professional, sales, service, household); description of the functions and organization of the offices of the metropolitan director of the Employment Service, and director of the New York State Employment Service; and office managers' statements on the organization of the New York City offices of the employment service.
Also information on the reception process, the application process, the placement process, counseling, selective counseling; employer visiting and promotion, and labor union relations.
Materials relating to the New York State Department of Labor, Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance include plans for expanding the Employment Service (1937); procedures for processing benefit claims (1937); and plans for expanding the Employment Service in metropolitan regions (1937).
Also minutes of the New York State Unemployment Insurance Advisory Council (1947-1949) and reports on merit rating (1939), experience rating (1940), postwar unemployment insurance (1944), collections and delinquencies (1943).
Other reports include that to the Social Security Administration, Bureau of Employment Security on the program of improving unemployment insurance office operations and establishing proper time factors; the report on unemployment insurance problems submitted to the Joint Legislative Committee on Industrial and Labor Conditions (1946); the record of a joint meeting of the Joint Legislative Committee on Unemployment Insurance and the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance (1950); a report by the Social Security Administration on problems involved in the elimination of wage records; letters from Marion B. Folsom (Eastman Kodak Co.) regarding the farm placement situation; a Social Security Administration budget survey of the Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance (1947), with a summary of the Division's operations; a report on the present system of unemployment in New York (1949); a report on the history and operations of the Miami claims office by the Division's Planning Office (1948); a report of the Division on employer payments and liabilities (1947); a report from M. Joseph Tierney (director of the Employment Service) to Milton O. Loysen on the application process (1948); the transcript of a meeting of the Committee on Amendments (1948); a speech by Milton O. Loysen on "How the Young-Demo Law Affects Business"; and relevant statistical and financial studies.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 20, 2015
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 21, 2017
Employment agencies -- New York (State) -- New York; Employment agencies -- New York (State); Employment agencies -- United States; Unemployment insurance -- New York (State); Labor supply -- New York (State) -- Statistics; Unemployment -- New York (State) -- New York; Corsi, Edward, 1896-1965; Folsom, Marion B. (Marion Bayard), 1893-1976; Goodwin, Robert C.; Gray, Herman A.; Loysen, Milton O.; Miller, Frieda S. (Frieda Segelke), 1889-1973; Morrison, Nathan; Tierney, M. Joseph; Eastman Kodak Company; New York (State). Department of Labor; New York (State). Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance; New York (State). Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance. Advisory Council; New York (State). Division of Unemployment Insurance. Advisory Council; New York (State). Legislature. Joint Committee on Industrial and Labor Conditions; New York (State). Legislature. Joint Committee on Unemployment Insurance; New York (State). State Employment Service; United States. Social Security Administration; United States. Social Security Board. Bureau of Research and Statistics
3834363
- Tax and Wage Records Bureau Interpretation Service, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  State of New York Department of Labor, Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance
- Occupations of Applicants for Work, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  September 1939. New York City Active File of New York State Employment Service
- Compilation of Material Implementing the Program of Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  January 15, 1948. Rules, Regulations, Administrative Interpretation, Federal and Sate Statutes and Agreements
- Compilation of Material Implementing the New York State Unemployment Insurance Law, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  January 15, 1947. Rules, Regulations, Administrative Interpretation, Federal and Sate Statutes and Agreements. 2 copies.
- Age, Sex, and Occupation of Applicants for Work in New York City, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  December, 1939. An Inventory of te New York State Employment Service
- Record of Joint Meeting of Joint Legislative Committee on Unemployment Insurance and State Advisory Council on Placement andd Unemployment Insurance, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  June 9, 1950.
- The Unemployment Insurance Tax Credit Plan in New York State: Preliminary Report, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  October, 1945. State of New York, Department of Labor, Bureau of Research and Statistics, Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance
- Labor Market Letter Statistical Review, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Annual Summary. State of New York, Department of Labor, Bureau of Research and Statistics, Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance
- Report on Unemployment Insurance Problems, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  October 15, 1946. State of New York, Department of Labor, Planning Office, Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance
- Report of Unemployment Insurance State Advisory Council to the Governor and Legislature of the State of New York on the Subject of Merit Rating Pursuant to Section 518-4 of the Labor Law, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  April 10, 1939.
- Problem of Prompt Follow-Up of Employers Who Fail to File Reports, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  July 6, 1942.
- Problem of Prompt Follow-Up of Employers Who Submit Reports Unaccompanied by Payments and Who have Not Previously Been Delinquent, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  July 6, 1942. Includes: Problem of the Allocation of Functions in the Registration Control Unit and Adjustment Unit of this Employer Contribution Section. Also includes: Problem of Selection of Delinquen Accounts for Referral to the Collection Section.
- Program of Improving Unemployment Insurance Office Operations and Establishing Proper Time Factors Thereof, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Report to Social Securit Administration, Bureau of Employment Security by Claims Bureau, Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance, New York State
- Status of Approved Deferred Payment Agreements as of May 23, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  June 18. 1942.
- Quarterly Report n Job Placement, Unfilled Job Openings, Employment Service Applicants, and Benefit Claimants., 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Includes reports for Buffalo (December 1947 - February 1948), Syracuse (December 1947 - February 1948), Utica (December 1947 - February 1948), and Rochester (February 1948).
- Blank Unemployment Insurance Claim Forms (Canada), 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Report to the Unemployment Insurance State Advisory Council and Employment Service State Advisory Council, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  January 23, 1941. Report 1940-no.12 for December 1940.
- Report on Status of Delinquency and Delinquency Control, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  January 14, 1942. Tax and Wage Records Bureau. Incluldes correspondence from June and July 1942.
- An Act to amend the labor law, in relation to retirement rights of reinstated employees, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  April 7, 1947. 1948 Program Bill no.11.
- Reports to the Unemployment Insurance State Advisory Council, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  June 20, 1947. Includes: Social Security Administration Budget Survey of the Division; Latest Sumary (for May 1947) of the Division's Operations; Attorney General's Opinion on the Proper Method of Computing th "Benefit Experience Index" for Jobbers and Co
- Reports to the Unemployment Insurance State Advisory Council, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  June 23, 1947. Includes: Minutes of the Meeting of the Council on February 13, 1947; Letters from Mr. Folsom and Representatives Hope and Zimmerman, on farm placement situation.
- Report to the Unemployment Insurance State Advisory Council, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  July 1, 1947. Includes: Speech by Mr. Loysen on "How the Young-Demo Low Affects Business"; Interpretation Service issued by the Tax and Wage Records Bureau (see Box 1, ff 1).
- 1948 Legislative Program, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  July 1, 1947. Preliminary Disposition of Program Referendum no.2-47.
- Form of Claims Bureau Subpeona, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  July 2, 1947. Policy Referendum no.5-47. Due on July 21, 1947.
- Discontinuance of a weekly report entitled "Unemployment Insurance Claims of Workers Involved in Strikes", 1947 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  June 27, 1947.
- Reports to the Unemployment Insurance State Advisory Council, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  July 8, 1947. Includes: Special Table on Trends in Referee Decisions by Issue, 1940- 1946; Special Set of Tables Comparing Relief Payments with Provisions in Recent Bills on Dependents' Allowances; "Labor Market Letter" with Area Breakdowns, for June 1947.
- Council Memorandum, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  July 16, 1947. Cover memorandum only for reports to Council, reports no longer included in collection.
- Correspondence, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  November 1947. Two letters by Herman A. Gray to Milton O. Loysen and one letter by W. O. Hake to Nathan Morrison.
- Wage Reporting on Request, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  November 21, 1947. Planning.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  November 25, 1947. Includes: Letter from Mr. Loysen on the costs of administering the tax credit plan, particularly the Young-Demo amendments; Division's request for funds to provide for the farm placement program; Summary of employment, earnings, and hou
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  November 26, 1947. Includes: Bill no.3 "Time Limitations; Contribution Liability" submitted by Mr. Loysen.
- Minutes of the 148th Meeting of the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  January 15, 1948.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  January 30, 1948. Includes: Report prepared by the Social Security Administration on the problems involved in the "elimination of Wage Records."
- Local Office Activities, Composition of Unemployed Applicants, and Reasons Why Jobs Remain Unfilled in New York City, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  December 1947 - February 1948.
- Memorandums Concerning New York State Senate and Assembly Legislative Bills, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Regulation 41 "Reporting By Benefit Claimants", 1948 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  February 9, 1948. Planning.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  February 11, 1948. Includes: Additional Studies Relating to "Package Bill"; Revised Version of Amendment to Regulation 41 "Reporting By Benefit Claimants" (see Box 1, ff 36); Additional material mentioned, but no longer included.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  February 13, 1948. Includes: Second Draft, Draft B, of the "Pakcage" Bill.
- Reporting Questions: Information to be Provided by Employers and Claimants, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  February 18, 1948.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  February 18, 1948. Includes: Report on the Employment Service Active File; Report Prepared by the Division in Connection with the "Package" Bill; Division's Latest Bulletin (February 10, 1948); Seven Memoranda on Outside Bills; "Compilation of he Social S
- Quarterly Report n Job Placement, Unfilled Job Openings, Employment Service Applicants, and Benefit Claimants., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  February 18, 1948. Planning: Selected Employment Offices (September - November 1947).
- Employment Service Operations in New York City, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  February 19, 1948 (Corrected); February 16, 1948 (Original).
- 1947 Report of the New York State Advisory Council, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  February 19, 1948.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  February 20, 1948. Includes: Corrected Memorandum on "Employment Service Operations in New York City" (see Box 1, ff 42); "B Series" memoranda on bills introduced in the Legislature on unemploymen insurance; Library Circulars nos.9 and 10 on New York Stat
- Council Memorandum, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  March 4, 1948. Cover memorandum only for reports to Council, reports no longer included in collection.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  March 5, 1948. Includes: Stenographic transcript of a meeting of the Committee on Amendments (February 16, 1948); Brief Summary of the Division's Budgetary Situation; 1947 Recommendations of the Social Securit Adminisration; Latest Release (March 1, 1948)
- Council Memorandum, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  March 8, 1948. Cover memorandum only for reports to Council, reports no longer included in collection.
- The Application Process, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  March 17, 1948. Report by M. Joseph Tierney, Director of the Employment Service. Excerpts from "The Emergence of a New Public Employment Service" by Jess T. Hopkins as quoted and discussed in Mr. Tierney's report. The full report is not included.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  March 27, 1948. Includes: Administrative Finance; Legislation; Employment Servic Active File; Court Decision on Collections and Delinquencies; Labor Market Reports; The Division's Budget; Miscellaneous.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  March 30, 1948. Includes: Package Bill on the Benefit Formula; Personnel; Newspaper Article on Florida Claimants.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  March 31, 1948. Incluces: Court Decision on "Wages Paid"; Article on "Recent Developments in Cash Sickness Insurance"; Minutes of the Advisory Council February 5, 1948 Meeting.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  April 1, 1948. Includes: "Report on the Division's Personnel Situtation"; Revised Chart Showing Examination Status of "Positions for Which No Lists Are Available"; Chart Showing "Results of Recent Canvasses of Civil Service Lists by DPUI."
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  April 2, 1948. Includes: Labor Market Reports Showing Types of Job Applicants and Unfilled Job Openings.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  May 3, 1948. Includes: Letter form Mr. Loysen concerning amendments to Regulations 40 and 41.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  May 4, 1948. Includes: Division's Report on Disqualifications of Florida Benefit Claimants; Budget; State Personnel News.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  May 6, 1948. Inlcudes: Employer Job Orders Containing Discriminatory Specifications; The "Labor Market Letter" or April 1948; Farm Placement.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  May 10, 1948. Includes: Preliminary National Economic Assumption, Fiscal Year 1950; Division Statement on the Operations of the Field Audit Section in 1947; Operations of Review and Control Section, Counsel's Office, March 1948.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  May 13, 1948. Includes: Costs of Administering the Tax Credit Plan; Florida.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  may 17, 1948. Includes: Bill, Prepared by the Interstate Conference of Employment Security Agencies, to Revise the Present System of Financing he Administration of Unemployment Insurance.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  May 20, 1948. Includes: Regulations of the Industrial Commissioner; Package Bill.
- History and Operation of Experimental Offices, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  May 25, 1948. Planning.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  May 28, 1948. Includes: The MacKinnon Bill on Administrative Funding.
- Local Office Activities, Composition of Unemployed Applicants, and Reasons Why Jobs Remain Unfilled in New York City, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  March - May 1948.
- Schedule of Budget Estimates: First Supplement Requestiong Funds to Provide for the Farm Placement Program, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  November 14, 1947. For the Period January 1, 1948 to June 30, 1948.
- News Release Announcing the Bureau of Employment Security Appointments, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  July 12, 1948. File no.DDI-29. General Administration Letter no.106.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  July 14, 1948. Includes: Administrative Financing; Regulations of the Industrial Commissioner; Two Court Decisions Affecting Collections and Delinquencies; Latest Edition of the Unemployment Insurance Booklet.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  July 20, 1948. Includes: Federal Employment Security Set-Up; Attorney General's Opinion on Section 578 "Non-Liability of Penalty and Interest"; Court Decision on Unemployment Insurance Coverage.
- Proposed Revision in Method of Processing Wage Records, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  July 21, 1948.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  August 12, 1948. Includes: Report "Hisotry and Operations of the Miami Claims Office."
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  October 28, 1948. Inlcudes: Bill on "Coverage and Equalizing Contributions."
- Correspondence, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  From February and March 1948.
- Report on the Present System of Unemployment Insurance in New York State, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  November 10, 1949. Inlcudes: Milton O. Loysen letter to Edward Corsi regarding report.
- Reports to the State Advisory Council on Placement and Unemployment Insurance, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  January 10, 1950. Includes: Excerpts from Recommendations made by T. L. Evans; Minutes of Council Meeting of December 28, 1949.
- Unemployment Compensation in the Post-War Period, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  December 1944. Suggestions for Expanding and Perfecting State Unemployment Compensation Systems and a Digest of State and Federal Provisions. By the Council of State Governments.
- Should State Unemployment Insurance Be Federalized?, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  By Herman Gray. American Enterprise Association National Economic Problems no.419. 3 copies.
- Railroad Social Insurance: Favored Treatment Verses Unform Social Insurance, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  By Rainard B. Robbins. American Enterprise Assciation National Economic Problems no.405.
- The National Health Program Scheme: An Analysis of the Wagner-Murray Health Bill (S. 1606), 1946 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  By Earl E. Muntz. American Enterprise Assciation National Economic Problems no.418A.
- Plans for Expanding the Employment Service in th Metropolitan Area, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  July 23, 1937. State of New York, Department of Labor, Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance.
- Plans for Expanding the Employment Service, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  July 27, 1937 (Revised), July 22, 1937 (Original). State of New York, Department of Labor, Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance.
- Central Office Procedure for Processing Benefit Claims, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  September 1, 1937. State of New York, Department of Labor, Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance.
- Central Office Procedure for Processing Benefit Claims, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  September 23, 1937. State of New York, Department of Labor, Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance.
- Material Pertaining to Frequency of Visits of Unemployed Workers to Employment Offices and Payment of Benefit Claims, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  October 10, 1937.
- Rules and Procedure in Regard to Disputed Claims Under the Unemployment Insurance Law, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  January 1938. State of New York, Department of Labor, Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance. 2 copies.